hideout-leather.co.uk 2018-09-01

# Hideout Leather - Privacy

**Privacy Policy**

This privacy policy sets out how Hideout Leather uses and protects any information that you give us when you use this website.

Hideout Leather is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, and then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

**We will never pass any of your personal details or e-mail address to any other organisation.**

**Contact Details**

Full name of legal entity: **Hideout Leather (2001) Ltd**

Email address: **[info@hideout-leather.co.uk](mailto:info@hideout-leather.co.uk)**

Postal address: **The stables, Goldstones Farm, Radwinter Road, Ashdon, Essex, CB10 2LZ**

It is very important that the information we hold about you is accurate and up to date.

Please let us know if at any time your personal information changes by emailing us at [info@hideout-leather.co.uk](mailto:info@hideout-leather.co.uk)

  **What data we collect, why we collect it and how we process it**

**Customer Data** that includes data relating to any purchases of goods and/or services such as your name, title, billing address, delivery address email address, phone number, contact details, purchase details and your card details. We process this data to supply the goods and/or services you have purchased and to keep records of such transactions.

**Communication Data** that includes any communication that you send to us whether that be through the contact form on our website, through email, text, social media messaging, social media posting or any other communication that you send us. We process this data for the purposes of communicating with you, for record keeping and for the establishment, pursuance or defence of legal claims.

**User Data** that includes data about how you use our website and any online services together with any data that you post for publication on our website or through other online services. We process this data to operate our website and ensure relevant content is provided to you, to ensure the security of our website, to maintain back- ups of our website and/or databases and to enable publication and administration of our website, other online services and business.

**Technical Data** that includes data about your use of our website and online services such as your IP address, your login data, details about your browser, length of visit to pages on our website, page views and navigation paths, details about the number of times you use our website, time zone settings and other technology on the devices you use to access our website. The source of this data is from our analytics tracking system. We process this data to analyse your use of our website and other online services, to administer and protect our business and website, to deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and to understand the effectiveness of our advertising. 

From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests.

**Sensitive Data**

We do not collect any Sensitive Data about you. Sensitive data refers to data that includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data. We do not collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

Where we are required to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of the contract between us and you do not provide us with that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract (for example, to deliver goods or services to you). If you don’t provide us with the requested data, we may have to cancel a product or service you have ordered but if we do, we will notify you at the time.

**Safety & Security of your Information**

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure and protected to the highest standard. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. The Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software we use encrypts the information you input, ensuring that it is virtually impossible for unauthorised parties to read any information that you provide. We may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent where this is required or permitted by law.

**How we use cookies**

A cookie is a small pieces of data or text files which asks permission to be stored by your web browser on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual and they allow a website to personalise your shopping experience. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

Our cookies do not contain any personal information about you and are only used to determine your browser and user preferences for our site. You can choose to accept or decline those cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can set your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. You should still be able to use our site without cookies enabled, but you may lose a certain level of functionality and may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

**How to delete cookies**

If you want to delete any cookies that are on your computer the “help section” in your browser should provide instructions on how to locate the file or directory that stores cookies. Alternatively, you can click on the links provided below.  Please note that by deleting or disabling future cookies your experience of our sites may be affected.

**  Links to other websites**

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

**Controlling your personal information**

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

  * whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes
  * if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at info@hideout-leather.co.uk

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

  **Data Retention   **

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

When deciding what the correct time is to keep the data for we look at its amount, nature and sensitivity, potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure, the processing purposes, if these can be achieved by other means and legal requirements.

For tax purposes the law requires us to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for six years after they stop being customers.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

**Disclosure of your personal data**

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below:

  * Service providers who provide IT and system administration services.
  * Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers.
  * Government bodies that require us to report processing activities.
  * Delivery companies

We require all third parties to whom we transfer your data to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We only allow such third parties to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

**Your Rights**

Under the new General Data Protection Regulation [GDPR] of 25th May 2018, you have the following rights with regards to your data:

  * Right to be Informed- You have the right to be informed about the collection and use of your personal data. This Privacy Policy should provide you with the information you need to understand how Hideout Leather (2001) Ltd uses your data. We regularly review our Privacy Policy and will update you on any changes we make.
  * Right of Access- You have the right to access the personal data that Hideout Leather (2001) Ltd holds for you.
  * Right to Rectification- You have the right to have inaccurate personal data rectified, or completed if it is incomplete.
  * Right to Erasure- You have the right to have any personal data we hold to be deleted.  The right to erasure is also known as ‘the right to be forgotten’.
  * You can unsubscribe from our newsletters at any time. This will not erase your data from any other service you have signed up for, but it will stop any marketing emails being sent to you.
  * Right to Restriction- You have the right to request the restriction or suppression of your personal data. This means Hideout Leather (2001) Ltd are permitted to store your personal data, but not use it. However, this may make the delivery of certain services impossible.
  * Right to Data Portability- The right to data portability allows you to obtain and reuse the personal data Hideout Leather (2001) Ltd holds on you for your own purposes across other services. This allows you to move, copy or transfer personal data easily from one IT environment to another in a safe and secure way, without hindrance to usability.
  * Right to Object- You have the right to object to Hideout Leather (2001) Ltd processing your data if you believe we do not have a legitimate reason for processing it, for example, direct marketing. Please direct any objections you have to us at [info@hideout-leather.co.uk](mailto:info@hideout-leather.co.uk)
  * Rights in relation to automated Decision Making & Profiling- This right refers to data processing that is done automatically without human involvement. In the case of Hideout Leather (2001) Ltd, this refers to our newsletter and websites, where we may use information we collect to tailor our marketing messages and product information to you.

You can make requests regarding any of these rights via an email to [info@hideout-leather.co.uk](mailto:info@hideout-leather.co.uk) or telephone: 01799 584828. We will action these requests free of charge within 4 weeks of the request being received.

Alternatively, if you wish to change your existing preferences in relation to receiving marketing information please go to My Account where you can review and update your details accordingly.

You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or OR by emailing us at [info@hideout-leather.co.uk](mailto:info@hideout-leather.co.uk)  at any time.

 If you opt out of receiving marketing communications this opt-out does not apply to personal data provided as a result of other transactions, such as purchases, warranty registrations etc.

If you have a concern about Hideout Leather (2001) Ltd’s information rights practices you can contact the ICO directly
